A Finding Aid to the Sidney C. Woodward Papers, 1823-1963, bulk 1915-1932, in the Archives of American Art AAA.woodsidn
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence and Collected Letters, 1823-1963; Series 1; 2.2 Linear feet Box 1-3
  - Schrafft, W. E., 1934; 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Scully, Russell A., 1962 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Seyffert, Leopold G., circa 1935 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Snell, Henry Bayley, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Sparrow, Walter Shaw, 1931; 1901 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Spaulding, John T., undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Spear, Arthur, 1931; 1928 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Spencer, Robert, 1925-1926; 1923; 1921 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Sturges, Dwight Case, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Swisher, Allan, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Symons, George Gardner, circa 1920-1922 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - T, Miscellaneous, circa 1845-1942 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Talbot, Beatrice Bill (Mrs. Fritz B. Talbot)
    Taylor, Leonard Campbell
    Taylor, William Ladd
    Thayer, Abbott Handerson
    Thompson, Leslie Prince
    Tonner, Florence T.
    Topham, Frank W. W.
    Trebilcock, Paul
    Turner, Charles Yardley
    Turner, H.
    Tushingham, Sidney
    Tyson, Carroll Sargent, Jr.
  - Taft, Lorado, 1919; 1922 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Talbot, Grace Helen, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Tarbell, Edmund Charles, circa 1923-1931 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Thompson, George Albert, circa 1921 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Traver, George A., 1925; 1927 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Turner, Helen M., circa 1925 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Tuttle, Henry Emerson & Isabel Hollister, circa 1924-1929 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Ufer, Walter, 1922; 1925 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Uwins, Thomas, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    Uwins, Thomas
  - V, Miscellaneous, 1886; 1927 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    Van Elten, Hendrick Dirk Kruseman
    Vezin, Charles
  - Vincent, Harry Aiken, circa 1924-1929 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Volkert, Edward Charles, circa 1922-1924 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - W, Miscellaneous, circa 1877-1963 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    Wales, George Canning
    Ward, Edgar Melville
    Warner, Everett Longley
    Watrous, Harry W.
    Way, Andrew John Henry
    Weber, Frederick Theodore
    Webster, E. Ambrose
    Weir, John Ferguson
    Wedgwood, Geoffrey
    White, C. Scott
    White, Elsie A.
    Wickley, Harry
    Wiggins, Carleton
    Williams, Gluyas
    Wingate, Carl
    Williard, Helen D.
    Winslow, Guy M.
    Wolchonok, Louis
    Woodard, Mrs. Lee
    Worcester Art Museum
    Wyeth, Newell Coners
    Wyllie, William L.
  - Walker, B. Eure, 1926-1931 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Warlow, H. Gordon, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Warren, Harold Broadfield, 1931; 1923 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Washburn, Cadwallader, 1918-1919 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Waugh, Frederick Judd, circa 1921-1924 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Wendel, Theodore, circa 1930 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Wiggins, Guy, 1924; 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Wilder, Arthur B., 1933 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Wilkinson, Norman, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Williams, Frederick Ballard, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Wilson, Stanley R., 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Woodbury, Charles Herbert, 1923; 1933 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Woodward, Robert Strong, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Woodward, Stanley, 1910-1963 (Box 2, Folder 84-101)
  - Woodward, Stanley, undated (Box 2, Folder 102-107)
  - Woodward, Stanley, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-7)
  - Y, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Yarrow, William Henry Kemble
    Young, Mahonri M.
  - Unidentified Letters, circa 1922-1933 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Biographical Material, 1918; Series 2; 1 Folders Box 3
  Biographical material consists of two military records of Woodward's appointment from Private First Class to second lieutenant in the Aviation Section of the Signal Reserve Corps, as well as an honorable discharge certificate from the Army of the United States.
  - Military Records, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Writings, circa 1880-1940; Series 3; 0.1 Linear feet Box 3
  Found here are manuscripts written by C. Lewis Hind and Elizabeth Robins Pennell, as well as a list of artist letters and miscellaneous writings by Woodward including lecture notes.
  - C. Lewis Hind Manuscripts, undated (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
  - Elizabeth Robins Pennell Manuscripts, undated (Box 3, Folder 14-17)
  - List of Artist Letters, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, undated; 1934 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
- Printed Material, circa 1880-1963; Series 4; 0.4 Linear feet Box 3-4
  Printed material consists of exhibition catalogs featuring Stanley Woodward and Casson Galleries exhibition catalogs, newspaper clippings of news stories regarding Sidney and Stanley, a World War I Navy recruiting poster catalog, as well as various books relating to the topic of art. Miscellaneous printed material consists of a lecture announcement, a catalog of etching artworks, a high school graduation brochure, and a playbill. Two books, Color and Method in Painting and The Etched Work of Franics Seymour Haden, within this series include inserted letters, photos, and added annotations. See the Correspondence and Collected Letters series for additional letters relating to these works.
  - Casson Galleries Catalogues, 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Color and Method in Painting by Ernest W. Watson, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Considerations on Engraving by Timothy Cole, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Copley Society Loan Collection of Pictures of Fair Women, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1919-1963 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Stanley Woodward Exhibition Catalogues, 1925; 1956; undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - The Etched Work of Francis Seymour Haden, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Whistler's Etchings, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - World War I Navy Recruiting Poster Catalog, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1923-1950 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Photographs, 1910s-1940s; Series 5; 4 Folders Box 4
  Found here are reference photographs of various artworks as well as personal photographs, which include photos of a portrait relief of Augustus Saint Gaudens, Stanley Woodward in a theater production, a Russell Hyde painting class, and a portrait of J. F. Bouchor.
  - Personal Photographs, 1910s-1940s (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Artwork, 1920s-1940s (Box 4, Folder 12-14)
- Scrapbooks, circa 1920-1940; Series 6; 0.7 Linear feet Box 5, BV 6-7
  Found here are three bound scrapbooks and one folder of loose scrapbook pages. Two scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings of Woodward’s column in The Christian Science Monitor; one scrapbook contains exhibition catalogs and announcements from the Casson Galleries as well as news clippings of art reviews, most of which were written by Woodward; and one scrapbook purchased by Woodward contains letters, autographs, photos, and art reproductions from 78 artists.
  - Artist's Works and Autographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Loose Scrapbook Pages, Christian Science Monitor, 1922-1923 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Christian Science Monitor Art Reviews, 1920-1922 (Box BV 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Miscellaneous Art Reviews; Casson Gallery Exhibition Announcements and Catalogues, 1921-1940 (Box BV 7)